Shashank Jaitly

A Physics Enthusiast, mixed with a little touch of programming. https://theprogrammerdude.github.io/

Shanti Nagar Housing Society, Howrah, Kolkata +91 9990295204 +91 7011572830 shashank.jaitly.98@gmail.com

BUSINESS

Crypto Future Trade

2020 - March, 2023

Started working on the Cryptocurrency Platform called Crypto Future Trade (CFT), worked my way to launch the platform successfully on Google Play Store and to make the company international. We are thriving to make the cryptocurrency market and community work together to form something ecstatic.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cftc.usd

EXPERIENCE

Future Trade

2021 - 2023

I've been working with future trade on their trading platforms and websites. Along with other web3 and blockchain projects

Freelance App and Web Developer

2019 - PRESENT

I've been working as a freelance web and app developer since 2020. I've developed a few applications in Android Studio, Ionic Framework, Games using Unity, etc. All project links are at the projects section.

Inzin Automotive, Delhi — Content Writer and Web Developer

2019 - 2020

Responsible for the development of articles for their blog, and developed two of their websites, https://www.inzin.in/ and https://inzinxpert.in/

Adway Info PVT LTD, Kolkata— Content Developer 2017 - 2018

Researching topics, and write full fledged articles and newsletters.

EDUCATION

Indira Gandhi National Open University, Delhi — Bachelor of

SKILLS

Web Development

Native App Development

(Android)

Hybrid App Development

Game Development

Video Editing

Web3

Solidity

Remix

ERC-721 Token

SOFTWARES AND TOOLS

VS Code

Unity Engine

Github

Firebase

Photoshop

Premiere Pro

Vegas Pro

Ionic

Android Studio (Java)

Flutter

NodeIs

LANGUAGES

Hindi, English

Science, Physics Major

2016 - 2021

Enrolled in the B. Sc. Physics course in IGNOU, in the mid of 2016, and due to some circumstances and COVID-19, it got delayed.

G. R. Sr. Sec. School, Delhi — High School

2016

Completed my high school from G. R. Sr. Sec. School,

PROJECTS

DevelopedByDude— Personal Blog

DevelopedByDude is a personal blog, written in angular and made possible using firebase for backend functionalities.

https://developedbydude.web.app/home

MusikTok — Tiktok Like Application

The application was developed to function like tiktok with a video editor and various UI screens. I've developed the frontend part of the application in Android Studio.

Story — Story Writing Application

Story is a story writing application, developed single handedly by myself. Technologies used – Ionic Framework and Firebase.

Link -

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1EuTzew346zG5GP9tM-7fa8HiTNnMmR DI/view?usp=sharing

Ball Story — Android Game Prototype

Ball Story is a simple android prototype 2D platformer game. Technologies used - Unity Engine and Photoshop.

Link - https://theprogrammerdude.itch.io/ball-story

NewsHub — News App

NewsHub is a news application that displays news(top headlines) and is based on different categories.

Technologies used - Flutter, NewsApi.

Link -

https://github.com/theprogrammerdude/NewsHub/blob/main/app-release.apk

HOBBIES

Working Out, Gaming, YouTube

ADDITIONAL LINKS

YouTube -

https://youtube.com/channel/ UCWA7UTHFX13sJzTCfTjE2_w

Github -

https://github.com/theprogrammerdude

Itch.io -

https://theprogrammerdude.itch.io/

Cartizo India — Ecommerce Platform

CartizoIndia is an ecommerce platform. I developed the website for the New Delhi Based Startup.

Technologies used - Wordpress

Link - http://cartizoindia.com/

CodingBits — Wordpress Website

CodingBits is a Wordpress Website.

Technologies used - Wordpress

Link - https://codingbits.co.in/